Fritz Kreisler Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1845-1966 (Box 1-13, 23)
  - Kreisler as Composer (Box 1-5, 13, 23)
    - Viennese love song, Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil, unfinished; 6 p. (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Rapsodic[sic] fantasietta "alla Viennese" for violin & piano, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 16 p.; Also ozalid of holograph; Uniform title: Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Excerpt from Viennes[sic] rhapsodic fantasietta, Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 16 p.; August 1951, Stockbridge, Mass.; Uniform title: Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta (Box-folder 4/14)
    - [Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta. Excerpt], Holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil with pasteovers; [15 p.]; On end paper: Original mss. before cuts were made. This is not the recorded version.; Uniform title: Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta. Excerpt (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Sketch to Viennese Rapsody, Holograph in pencil; 16 p.; Uniform title: Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta. Sketch (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta New York: Charles Foley, 1948., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part; 21 p.; Plate no. K1114 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Choral study, Holograph sketch in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Gemächliches Walzer tempo, Holograph sketch in pencil, incomplete; 7 p.; Also ozalid of holograph sketch (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Leclair - Tambourin, D major, Holograph sketch in ink, incomplete; 2 p.; On back: Sketch of an "original" composition "in the style of" Leclair.ot the same work as the transcription of the same title published Mainz, B. Schott's Söhne [1913] (Box-folder 5/3)
    - [Sketchbook], Bound holograph sketches for violin and piano, in pencil and ink; 46 p.; Includes: Allegretto von Boccherini Tambourin chinois Caprice viennois (Box-folder 4/18)
    - [Sketches. Miscellaneous and unidentified], Holograph sketches mostly in pencil; 65 p. (Box-folder 5/4-5)
  - Kreisler as Arranger (Box 5-13)
    Arranged alphabetically by composer.
    - Compositions Attributed to a Single Composer (Box 6-13)
      - Albéniz, Isaac
        - [España. Tango; arr.], Holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 4 p.; Uniform title: España. Tango; arr. (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian
        - Concerto in A minor London: Novello & Co., 1902., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive alterations in pencil by Kreisler; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, S. 1041, A minor; arr.; Arranged by August Wilhelmj and James Brown (Box-folder 6/2)
        - Violin concerto in D minor, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in ink; 47 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, S. 1052a, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 6/3)
        - Partita, E major Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1928., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part; 31 p. (Box-folder 6/4)
        - Sonaten und Partiten für Violine allein, Heft 1 & 2 Berlin: Ed. Bote & G. Bock, 1908., Printed violin score; 66 p.; Edited by Joseph Joachim & Andreas Moser (Box-folder 11/1)
        - Air New York: G. Schirmer, 1904., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part; 3 p.; Arranged by August Wilhelmj; Uniform title: Suite, orchestra, S. 1068, D major. Air on the G string; arr. (Box-folder 11/2)
        - Suite, E moll [and] Fuge, G moll Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano, with alterations in pencil by Kreisler; 42 p.; Bound with: G. F. Händel, Sonate I-VI; Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d.; Uniform title: Suite, violin & contrabass, S. 1023, E minor; arr. (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van
        - 2 Romanzen London: Augener & Co., n.d., Printed score for violin and piano, with pencil annotations; 16 p.; Arranged by Gustav Jensen (Box-folder 11/3)
        - Cavatina in E-flat, op. 130, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in pencil and ink; 4 p.; Uniform title: Quartet, strings, no. 13, op. 130, B-flat major. Cavatina; arr. (Box-folder 6/6)
        - Romanzen Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano (11 p.) and violin part (6 p.); Uniform title: Romances, violin & orchestra, op. 40 & op. 50, G major & F major; arr.; Arranged by August Wilhelmj (Box-folder 11/4)
        - Sonata, op. 47 New York: G. Schirmer, 1894., Printed score for violin and piano; [40 p.]; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & piano, no. 9, op. 47, A major (Box-folder 11/5a)
        - Sonate (komponiert 1803) Leipzig: C. F. Peters, 1931., Printed score for violin and piano; 44 p.; Edited by Walther Davisson; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & piano, no. 9, op. 47, A major (Box-folder 11/5b)
        - Sonate für pianoforte und violine Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano; 40 p.; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & piano, no. 9, op. 47, A major (Box-folder 11/5c)
      - Berlin, Irving
        - Blue skies [arr.], Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano in pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 6/7)
      - Brahms, Johannes
        - Choral Prelude: "Es ist ein Ros' entsprungen", Manuscript violin part in ink; 1 p.; Transcribed for violin with piano accompaniment by A. Walter Kramer; Uniform title: Chorale preludes, op. 122. No. 8, Es ist ein' Ros' entsprungen; arr. (Box-folder 11/6)
        - Hungarian Dance (after Johannes Brahms) New York: Charles Foley, 1925., Uniform title: Hungarian dance, no. 17, F minor; arr. (Box-folder 6/8)
        - Concert Berlin: N. Simrock, n.d., Printed score for violin, violincello, and piano (47 p.), violin part (23 p.), and violincello part (23 p.); Neuere Werke für Kammermusik; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, violincello, orchestra, op. 102, A minor; arr. (Box-folder 11/7)
        - Walzer New York: Carl Fischer, 1916., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Edited by David Hochstein; Uniform title: Waltz, piano 4 hands, op. 39, no. 15, A major; arr. (Box-folder 11/8)
      - Bruch, Max
        - Fantasie, op. 46 Berlin: N. Simrock, 1880., Printed score for violin and piano; 35 p.; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 46; arr. (Box-folder 11/9)
        - Schwedische Tänze [op. 63], Bruch holograph violin part in ink; 12 p. (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Chaikovskii, Petr Il'ich
        - Konzert für Violine und Orchester, op. 35 Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive Kreisler pasteovers and alterations; 52 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin & orchestra, op. 35, D major; arr. (Box-folder 6/9)
        - Andante cantabile aus: Quartett op. 11 Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1925., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part; 8 p.; Uniform title: Quartet, strings, no. 1, op. 11, D major. Andante cantabile; arr. (Box-folder 6/10)
        - Scherzo, op. 42, no. 2 Leipzig: D. Rahter, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part, with extensive pasteovers and alterations; 16 p.; Uniform title: Souvenir d'un lieu cher. No. 2, Scherzo; arr. (Box-folder 6/11)
        - Chant sans paroles, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 3 p.; Uniform title: Souvenir de Hapsal. Chant sans paroles; arr. (Box-folder 6/12)
      - Chaminade, Cécile Louise Stéphanie
        - Chaminade, Kreisler holograph sketch in ink; 3 p.; Uniform title: Chanson espagnole; arr. (Box-folder 6/13)
        - Serenade Espagnole New York: Carl Fischer, 1915., Printed score for violin and piano, and violin part; 5 p. (Box-folder 6/14)
      - Chausson, Ernest
        - Poème pour violon et orchestre, op. 25 Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1898., Printed score for violin and piano, with annotations in ink and pencil (17 p.) and manuscript violin part in Kreisler's hand (4 p.) (Box-folder 11/11)
      - Chopin, Fryderyk Franciszek
        - Mazurka A major, Kreisler holograph sketch in pencil; 4 p.; Uniform title: Mazurka, piano, op. 33, no. 2, D major; arr. (Box-folder 6/15)
      - Corelli, Arcangelo
        - La folia, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; [16 p.]; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & continuo, op. 5, no. 2, D minor. La folia; arr. (Box-folder 6/16)
      - Debussy, Claude
        - La fille aux cheveux de lin (Extrait des Préludes), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 2 p.; Uniform title: Préludes, piano, Book 1. La fille aux cheveux de lin; arr. (Box-folder 6/17)
      - Dvorák, Antonin
        - [Slavonic dance, op. 46, no. 2, E minor; arr.] Berlin: N. Simrock, 1914., Printed score for violin and piano; 7 p.; Uniform title: Slavonic dance, op. 46, no. 2, E minor; arr. (Box-folder 6/18)
        - [Slavonic dance, op. 46, no. 3, G major; arr.] New York: Carl Fischer, 1914., Printed score for violin and piano; 7 p.; Uniform title: Slavonic dance, op. 46, no. 3, G major; arr. (Box-folder 6/19)
        - Songs my mother told me (Gypsy song), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 4 p.; Uniform title: Zigeunerlieder, op. 55. Als die alte Mutter; arr. (Box-folder 6/20)
      - Elgar, Edward
        - Concerto London: Novello & Co., 1910., Printer's proofs of violin part; 25 p.; On first page of music: Fritz Kreisler, with gratitude from Edward Elgar, Oct. 1910; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, op. 61 (Box-folder 11/12)
        - First sketch of violin concerto, 1905, Holograph sketch in pencil; 4 p. with attachment; On cover: To Fritz Kreisler, Nov. 1910, with admiration and gratitude [from] Edward Elgar; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, op. 61. Sketch (Box-folder 11/13)
      - Falla, Manuel de
        - Suite populaire Espagnole pour violon et piano d'après Siete canciones populares Españolas Paris: Max Eschig & Cie, 1925., Printed score for violin and piano, with pencil annotations; 24 p.; Uniform title: Canzones populares españolas; arr. (Box-folder 11/14)
        - La Jota, Spanish dance, Manuscript score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil (8 p.) and violin part in Kreisler's hand, in ink (2 p.); On cover: transcribed for violin and piano by de Falla together with Paul Kochanski; Uniform title: Canzones populares españolas. No. 6, La Jota; arr. (Box-folder 11/15)
        - Danse espagnole New York: Carl Fischer, 1926., Printed score for violin and piano; 11 p.; 2 copies; Uniform title: La vida breve. No. 1, Danza; arr. (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Fernandez-Arbós, Enrique
        - La Zambra Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1911., Printed score for violin and piano (15 p.) and violin part (6 p.); Uniform title: Trois morceaux de concert, op. 6. No. 1, La Zambra (Box-folder 12/1)
        - Guajiras Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, [1911]., Printed score for violin and piano (13 p.) and violin part (5 p.), and alternate version of violin solo for performance with orchestra (1 p.); Uniform title: Trois morceaux de concert, op. 6. No. 2, Guajiras (Box-folder 12/2)
        - Tango Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, [1911]., Printed score for violin and piano (12 p.) and violin part (6 p.); Uniform title: Trois morceaux de concert, op. 6. No. 3, Tango (Box-folder 12/3)
        - [Trois morceaux de concert, violin & orchestra, op. 6. No. 1, Zambra; arr.], Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 15 p.; Uniform title: Trois morceaux de concert, violin & orchestra, op. 6. No. 1, Zambra; arr. (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Foster, Stephen Collins
        - Old folks at home (Swanee river), Kreisler holograph sketches for violin and piano, in pencil and blue pencil; 10 p. (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Gaertner, Eduard
        - Viennese melody New York: Charles Foley, 1915, 1943., Printed score for violin and piano with alterations in ink (3 p.) and violin part (1 p.); Also printed: New York, 1943 (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Gluck, Christoph Willibald
        - Melodie Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1913., Printed score for violin and piano; 3 p.; Uniform title: Orfeo ed Euridice. No. 30, Melodia; arr. (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Godowsky, Leopold
        - Orientale, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in ink; [5 p.]; At end of music: Avon, May 22nd 1915 (Box-folder 7/6)
        - Larghetto lamentoso [and] Viennese New York: Carl Fischer, 1916., Printed score for violin and piano; [14 p.]; Violin part fingered and phrased by Fritz Kreisler; To my dear friends Harriet and Fritz Kreisler; Uniform title: Twelve impressions, violin & piano. No. 1, 12; Bound with: Debussy, Claude. La fille aux cheveux de lin; ed. Arthur Hartmann; Paris: A. Durand & Fils, 1910. Chabrier, Emmanuel. Scherzo-valse; arr. Ch. M. Loeffler; New York: G. Schirmer, 1909. Rachmaninoff, Sergei. Vocalise; arr. M. Press; Moscou; Edition russe de musique, 1916. Rachmaninoff, Sergei. Marguerite; Moscou: Edition russe de musique, 1916. (Box-folder 12/4)
      - Granados y Campiña, Enrique
        - Spanish dance, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 6 p.; Dated: July 4th 1915; Uniform title: Danzas españoles, piano, op. 37. No. 5, Playera; arr. (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Gretchaninoff, Alexandr
        - 2me sonate pour violon et piano, Holograph[?] score for violin and piano (47 p.) and vioin part (18 p.); Uniform title: Sonata, violin & piano, no. 2, op. 137 (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Haydn, Joseph
        - Hungarian rondo (Rondo all'ungarese), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, and violin part, in ink; 8 p.; Also included: Ozalid of holograph score; Uniform title: Concertos, harpsichord, 14. XVIII, 11, D major. Rondo all'ungarese; arr. (Box-folder 7/8)
        - Trio I Boston: Boston Music Company, n.d., Printed score for violin, violoncello, and piano (19 p.), violin part (7 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box-folder 12/6)
      - Hellmesberger, Josef, Sr.
        - Sechs Cadenzen Wien: Universal Edition, n.d., Printed violin I part (17 p.) and violin II part (3 p.); Includes cadenzas to: Beethoven, Ludwig van. Violin concerto in D major Beethoven, Ludwig van. Violin concerto in C major (fragment) Bach, Johann Sebastian. Violin concerto in A minor Bach, Johann Sebastian. Double concerto Paganini, Nicolò. Violin concerto in D major Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus. Concerto for violin and viola in E major (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Lalo, Edouard
        - Symphonie espagnole, pour violon principal & orchestre, op. 21 Paris: A. Durand & Fils, n.d., Printed violin score; 50 p. (Box-folder 12/8)
      - Mendelssohn, Felix
        - Concerto, op. 64 New York: G. Schirmer, 1895., Printed violin part; 16 p.; Edited by Henry Schradieck; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, op. 64; arr. (Box-folder 12/9)
      - Meyer, Konrad Ferdinand
        - Schnitterlied, Manuscript piano-vocal score in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Moussorgsky, Modest
        - Hopak New York: Charles Foley, 1924., Printed score?? and parts; [15 p.]; Arranged by Sergei Rachmaninoff (Box-folder 12/11)
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
        - Violin concerto no. 3 (G major), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink (36 p.), and violin part, in pencil (12 p.); Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 3, K. 216, G major; arr. (Box-folder 7/9)
        - Drittes Konzert (Köchel nr. 216) Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano, with extensive paste-overs and alterations; 27 p.; Edited by Carl Flesch; Herausgegeben von Carl Flesch; Klavierauszug von Ignaz Strasfogel; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 3, K. 216, G major; arr. (Box-folder 7/10)
        - Viertes Konzert Leipzig: C. F. Peters, 1910., Printed score for violin and piano with annotations and alterations; 24 p.; Edited by Henri Marteau; Klavierauszug von Aug. Göllner; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 4, D major; arr. (Box-folder 12/12)
        - Concerto #6 (E-flat major) K. 1776, Kreisler holograph full score (42 p.) and violin part (11 p.) in pencil; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 6, K. 286, E-flat major; arr. (Box-folder 7/11)
        - Violin concerto no. 6, E-flat major (Köchel 268), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 36 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 6, K. 286, E-flat major; arr. (Box-folder 7/12)
        - [Concertos, violin, no. 3-6. Cadenzas], Kreisler holograph score for violin, in pencil; 12 p.; Uniform title: Concertos, violin, no. 3-6. Cadenzas (Box-folder 7/13)
        - Rondo Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1913., Printed score for violin and piano (12 p.) and violin part (incomplete); Uniform title: Serenade, K. 248b (250), D major. Rondeau; arr. (Box-folder 7/14)
        - Konzertante Symphonie, Printed viola part with annotations and paste-overs in pencil; [12 p.]; Uniform title: Sinfonia concertante, violin, viola & orchestra, K. 320 (364), Eb major (Box-folder 12/13)
        - Konzertante Symphonie, Manuscript (violin?) score in pencil in Kreisler's hand; [2 p.]; At top (p. 1): Cadenza (possibly Mozart); At top (p. 2): closing - possibly to a Mozart? (Box-folder 12/13)
      - Nevin, Ethelbert Woodbridge
        - Sketch to Meithy[sic] like a rose, Kreisler holograph sketch for violin, in ink; 1 p.; After title: played with Geraldine Farrar's recording of it; Uniform title: Mighty lak' a rose (Box-folder 7/15)
      - Paganini, Nicolò
        - Kadenz zum letzten Satz des 1. ViolinKonzertes - D, Manuscript violin score in the hand of Wilhelm Schroer; 2 p.; In leicht ausführbarer Spielbezeichnung von Wilhelm Schroer; On cover: Prof. Fritz Kreisler in tiefer Verehrung; At end of music: Mai 1952, Germany; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 1, D major. Cadenza, I; arr. (Box-folder 13/1)
        - Konzertstück (1 Satz der Violin Konzert no. 1 D-dur) Neue Ausgabe von Fritz Kreisler, Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 88 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 1, op. 6, E-flat major. Allegro; arr. (Box-folder 7/16)
        - Concerto in one movement for violin and orchestra [by] Fritz Kreisler New York: Charles Foley, 1936., Printed full score; 100 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 1, op. 6. Allegro; arr. (Box-folder 7/17)
        - Concerto No. 2 (B minor), Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 134 p.; On cover: 1933; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 2, op. 7, B minor; arr. (Box-folder 8/1)
        - Violin concerto no. 2, B minor, Manuscript score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil (50 p.) and violin part in the hand of Fritz Kreisler, in pencil (12 p.); Edited by Camillo Sivori; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 2, op. 7, B minor; arr. (Box-folder 13/2)
        - Concerto no. 2 Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1909., Printed score for violin and piano (35 p.) and violin part (19 p.); Edited by A. Wilhelm; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 2, op. 7, B minor; arr. (Box-folder 13/3)
        - Variationen, 24te Caprice, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil, incomplete; 9 p.; Uniform title: Caprice, violin, no. 24, A minor; arr. (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Poldini, Eduard
        - En voyage (au tour de Vienne), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink over pencil (7 p.) and violin part in pencil (2 p.); Also includes: additional holograph score in pencil; 7 p. (Box-folder 8/3)
      - Rachmaninoff, Sergei
        - The alder tree New York: Carl Fischer, 1922., Printed score for violin and piano (5 p.) with holograph violin obligato part (1 p.) (Box-folder 8/4)
        - Preghiera (Prayer) from the 2nd movement of the Piano concerto no. 2, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 6 p.; At end of music: Transcribed by F. K. January 9th 1940; Uniform title: Concerto, piano, no. 2, op. 18, C minor. Preghiera; arr. (Box-folder 8/5)
        - Preghiera New York: Charles Foley, 1940., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, piano, no. 2, op. 18, C minor. Preghiera; arr. (Box-folder 8/6)
        - To the children Boston: Oliver Ditson, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; 5 p.; Uniform title: Fifteen songs, op. 26. No. 7, To the children; arr. (Box-folder 13/4)
        - Marguerite (Albumleaf) New York: Carl Fischer, 1926., Printed score for violin and piano; 7 p. (Box-folder 8/7)
        - Oh, cease thy singing maiden fair New York: Carl Fischer, 1922., Printed piano-vocal score; 7 p. (Box-folder 8/8)
        - Italian polka, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil with red pencil annotations; 4 p.; Uniform title: Polka italienne, piano, 4 hands; arr. (Box-folder 8/9)
        - Prelude in G minor, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 7 p.; Uniform title: Prelude, piano, op. 23, no. 5, G minor; arr. (Box-folder 8/10)
        - Oh, thou waving field of golden grain New York: Carl Fischer, 1922., Printed piano-vocal score; 5 p.; A. Tolstoi; English version by Geraldine Farrar; Uniform title: Six songs, op. 4. No. 5, Oh, thou waving field (Box-folder 13/5)
        - When night descends in silence New York: Carl Fischer, 1930., Printed piano-vocal score and violin part; 8 p. (Box-folder 8/11)
      - Ravel, Maurice
        - Pièce en forme de habanera, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 8/12)
        - Habanera, Third part of Rapsodie Espagnole New York: Carl Fischer, 1928., Printed violin part; 3 p.; Uniform title: Rapsodie espagnole, orchestra. No. 3, Habanera; arr. (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Rimskii-Korsakov, Nicolai Andreevich
        - Hymne au soleil (Sonnen-Hymne) aus der Oper Le coq d'or New York: Carl Fischer, 1919., Printed score for violin and piano; 7 p.; Uniform title: Le coq d'or. Hymn to the sun; arr. (Box-folder 8/14)
        - Russian fantasy for violin and orchestra, Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 43 p.; Uniform title: Fantasie de concert sur des thèmes russes, violin 7 orchestra, op. 33; arr. (Box-folder 8/15)
        - Fantasie sur des thèmes russes, newly edited and freely arranged by Fritz Kreisler, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 17 p.; On cover: December 1928; Uniform title: Fantasie de concert sur des thèmes russes, violin 7 orchestra, op. 33; arr. (Box-folder 8/16)
        - Fantasy on Russian themes New York: Carl Fischer, 1929., Printed score for violin and piano (17 p.) and violin part (7 p.); Also: 2 additional copies of score, one with pencilled cadenza pasteover; Uniform title: Fantasie de concert sur des thèmes russes, violin & orchestra, op. 33; arr. (Box-folder 8/17)
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille
        - 3e concerto pour violon et orchestre Paris: A. Durand & Fils, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive alterations and pasteovers; 45 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 3, op. 61, B minor; arr. (Box-folder 8/18)
        - Violin concerto, B minor, Kreisler holograph violin part in pencil; 12 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 3, op. 61, B minor; arr. (Box-folder 8/19)
      - Schubert, Franz
        - Ave Maria [and] Am Meer Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1909., Printed score for violin and piano; 9 p.; Arranged by A. Wilhelmj (Box-folder 13/6)
        - [Impromptu, piano, op. 142, no. 2, Ab major; arr.], Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 11 p.; At end of music: Oct. 26th 1933 on board S. S. Europe; Uniform title: Impromptu, piano, op. 142, no. 2, Ab major; arr. (Box-folder 9/1)
        - Rondo brillant, für Piano und Violine, op. 70 Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano (24 p.) and violin part (11 p.) with occasional alterations in pencil; Edition: [Neuausg.]; Schultze-Biesantz & M. Dello (Box-folder 13/7)
        - Rondo New York: Carl Fischer, 1917., Printed violin part; 7 p.; Arranged by Friedberg; Fingering and bowing by Fritz Kreisler; Uniform title: Sonata, D major, op. 53. Rondo; arr. (Box-folder 13/8)
      - Schumann, Robert
        - Fantasie op. 131, Copyist's full score in ink; 76 p.; Copyright notice paste on: Copyright 1936 by Charles Foley; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr. (Box-folder 9/2)